import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData: ExamData = {
    title: "Powered Flying Controls",
    questions: [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "The purpose of pulley wheels in cable control systems is:",
            "options": [
                "to ensure the cable tensions are equal throughout the system",
                "to change the direction of the control cable",
                "to ensure smooth operation of the system",
                "to prevent the cable from slackening"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "The purpose of the primary stops in a control system is:",
            "options": [
                "to set the range of movement of the control surface",
                "to enable the secondary stops to be correctly spaced",
                "to limit control movement to one direction only",
                "to set the control surface neutral position"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "The purpose of the secondary stops in a control system is:",
            "options": [
                "to reduce the control loads on the primary stops",
                "to limit control surface range in the event of primary stop failure",
                "to limit the secondary control system from excessive movement",
                "to remove the excess backlash in the controls"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "The purpose of the fairleads in a cable control system is to:",
            "options": [
                "alter the angle of deflection of the cables",
                "to guide the cables on to the pulley wheels",
                "to attach the cables to chain drives",
                "to keep the cable straight and clear of structure"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "In a cable control system cables are tensioned to:\n1. remove backlash from the control linkage\n2. provide tension on the turnbuckles\n3. provide positive action in both directions\n4. ensure the full range is achieved\n5. compensate for temperature variations",
            "options": [
                "1, 3 and 5 only",
                "3 only",
                "4 only",
                "all the above"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "In a cable control system the cables are mounted in pairs to:\n1. remove backlash from the control linkage\n2. provide tension on the turnbuckles\n3. provide positive action in both directions\n4. ensure the full range is achieved\n5. compensate for temperature variations",
            "options": [
                "1, 3 and 5 only",
                "3 only",
                "4 only",
                "all the above"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "In a manual flying control system the control inputs to the primary control surfaces:\n1. are reversible\n2. are irreversible\n3. are instinctive for the movement required\n4. are opposite for the movement required\n5. are limited in range by flight deck obstructions",
            "options": [
                "1 and 4 only",
                "2 and 4 only",
                "1 and 3 only",
                "1, 3 and 5 only"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "To yaw the aircraft to the right:",
            "options": [
                "the right rudder pedal is pushed forward and the rudder moves to the left",
                "the right rudder pedal is pushed forward and the rudder moves to the right",
                "the left rudder pedal is pushed forward and the rudder moves to the left",
                "the left rudder pedal is pushed forward and the rudder moves to the left"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "To roll the aircraft to the right:",
            "options": [
                "the rudder control is moved to the right, the right aileron moves up and the left down",
                "the aileron control is moved to the left and the right aileron moves up and the left down",
                "the aileron control is moved to the right and the right elevator goes up and the left one down",
                "the aileron control is moved to the right, the right aileron goes up and the left one down"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "The advantages of a cable control are:\n1. light, very good strength to weight ratio\n2. easy to route through the aircraft\n3. less prone to impact damage\n4. takes up less volume\n5. less bolted joints",
            "options": [
                "1, 2 and 4 only",
                "3 and 5 only",
                "1, 2 and 5 only",
                "all the above"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        }
    ]
}